Amazing grace how sweet the sound
That saved a wretch like me
I once was lost but now I'm found
Was blind but now I see
It was grace that taught my heart to fear
And grace my fears relieved
How precious did that grace appear
The hour I first believed
My chains are gone I've been set free
My God my Saviour has ransomed me
And like a flood His mercy reigns
Unending love amazing grace
Amazing grace how sweet the sound
That saved a wretch like me
I once was lost but now I'm found
Was blind but now I see
Amazing grace how sweet the sound
That saved a wretch like me
I once was lost but now I'm found
Was blind but now I see
My chains are gone I've been set free
My God my Saviour has ransomed me
And like a flood His mercy reigns
Unending love amazing grace
My chains are gone I've been set free
My God my Saviour has ransomed me
And like a flood His mercy reigns
Unending love amazing grace
My chains are gone I've been set free
My God my Saviour has ransomed me
And like a flood His mercy reigns
Unending love amazing grace
My chains are gone I've been set free
My God my Saviour has ransomed me
And like a flood His mercy reigns
Unending love amazing grace
Put your hands together for the amazing Christ.
Today, let's usher ourselves; let's look at the book of Jeremiah.
Jeremiah 31, let me take verse 34.
"No longer will they teach their neighbor, or say to one another, ‘Know the Lord',
because they will all know me, from the least of them to the greatest, declares the Lord,
for I will forgive their wickedness and will remember their sins no more.”
This is what the Lord says.
Are you there?
That verse 34; it is all about forgiveness.
FORGIVENESS AND UNFORGIVENESS
Forgiveness – you don’t give; you don't get.
That is all about forgiveness.
You don’t give; you don't receive.
Hallelujah!
Are you there?
Forgiveness – you don’t give; you don't get.
I mean, you don’t give; you don't receive.
You have a full detail about forgiveness in the Book of Mark 11 from verse 1 to the end.
Mark 11:1-end
About FORGIVENESS AND UNFORGIVENESS
What we have seen today is all about - you don't give; you don't receive.
Tell your neighbour.
[You don’t give; you don't receive.]
What you give is what you receive.
[What you give is what you receive.]
I cannot hear you.
If you give what you don’t need, you will receive what you don’t need.
If you give what your life depends on – what you cherish most,
you will receive what your life depends on – what you cherish most.
There are many material things we don't need.
You pretend to forgive...
There are things that you don't need, or you give your waste time, time you don't need.
Look at yourself here today.
It is not that this time is very important to you.
You are here because there is no other business out there, and nothing functions today.
You cannot cash money in the bank, there is nothing...
You are here as if you are giving God your best time.
What you give is what you receive.
If you give what you don't need; the material in your store, used tire...
Those tires that you know could lead to a death - and you are giving it to your neighbour.
Your neighbour needs a tire and you give him a tire - you are setting a trap for your neighbour.
You are about to kill your neighbour.
Many people died because of that.
You might have killed many people which you don't know - indirectly.
You say that you are not a murderer.
Who told that you are not a murderer?
What about those used tires you gave your friend in the past?
You heard that your friend had an accident...
It was the cause of the death.
Many Christians today are victims of the trap of unforgiveness.
Many of us have never felt the presence of God.
You just use an idea.
You don't know what it means to feel the presence of God.
How does He see people?
Does He shake people like this?
How?
Many have never felt the presence of God due to years of holding unforgiveness.
Due to what?
Years of what?
... of holding unforgiveness.
You are holding grief, grudges, pain of the past, bitterness, resentment in your heart
and you are expecting to feel the presence of God.
I am just telling you the reason why you don't know who God is.
You only read that God is good, nice, He is Saviour, Healer, Deliverer...
But to have Him - it is a different thing.
Many have never felt the presence of God due to years of holding unforgiveness.
Pain of the past, strife, claiming you are right;
you don’t know that unforgiving spirit will put you in the dark, outside God.
Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold pain.
Unforgiveness because of relations, friends, people that died, or that are alive...
Holding unforgiveness towards dead, alive, relatives, friends
and you are expecting to feel the presence of God...
God is looking for a free spirit.
You are not free.
You are not available.
Tell your neighbour, "You are not free.
You are not available".
I cannot hear you.
[You are not free.
You are not available.]
I cannot hear you.
[You are not free.
You are not available.]
Again.
[You are not free.
You are not available.]
You are not free.
You are not available.
If you should go into your heart, a lot is there - there is a conflict between faith and doubt,
love and hatred, good and bad.
Conflicts are going on.
You are not free.
You have to settle your account.
You must have a free spirit to attract the Spirit of God.
You are not free.
That is why you have never felt the presence of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Someone may have done a horrible thing to you.
For you to receive God, you must forgive.
You must forgive.
Someone may have done horrible things to offend you.
For you to receive God, you must forgive.
The question: How will I forgive?
You must first learn to forgive yourself.
Then, you can forgive others.
What you don’t have, you cannot give.
You can only give out what you have and you cannot give all you have.
Forgive yourself; then, forgive others.
Because everybody hurts somewhere.
Tell your neighbour, "Everybody hurts somewhere."
You must give them another chance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Everybody hurts somewhere.
You must give them another chance.
Because you are given another chance, that is why you are here today.
You are given another chance; that is why you are able to sit, talk and laugh freely.
There are many people who, right now, cannot walk freely.
They want to be here but could not.
You walk, talk, sit and hear, freely.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many who are better than you, who live right better than you, are in the graveyard.
In terms of "living right", when we compare them to you, and you say you live right and you are an obedient child,
they are more obedient than you - but yet they are at the graveyard.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Their dream hit the rock of disappointment.
Here you are
looking freely, sitting freely, talking freely.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Give them another chance.
Tell your neighbour.
[Give them another chance.]
Your accusers – give them another chance.
I cannot hear you.
Give them another chance.
Your offenders – give them another chance.
Your enemies – give them another chance.
Jesus never disconnected from those who had made mistakes with their lives.
Give them another chance.
Don’t forget where we are coming from.
You don’t give; you don’t get.
What you give is what you get.
If you give useless things – what you do not need, you will continue to receive what you don’t need.
You have been giving your waste time, time you don't need.
When you want to visit your friends, you make sure you have no other commitments before going there.
You only want to pray when you are in need of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Sunday service - your government made it possible for you to be free so that you can come.
It is like you have been encouraged to worship God.
You should stop to be encouraged to worship God, you should worship God.
Tell your neighbour, "Stop being encouraged - worship God".
You have been encouraged to worship God, that is why they have given you a day for worship - Sunday.
Your government, your authority is encouraging you to worship God,
that is why you are given a free day to come to church.
That should not be the salvation of your soul.
The salvation of your soul – you should worship God with all your heart, with all your soul.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
After today you will not worship or read your Bible until next Sunday.
The way you have been giving to God is the way you have been receiving from Him.
There are many areas in the Bible you have never read in your life.
You only look for a healing and blessing portion - psalm 35.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What you give is what you get.
So, forgiveness – what you give is what you get.
“I forgive you” – do you really mean it with all your heart?
"I forgive you."
Do you really mean it with all your heart or you say this for selfish, classic and material reasons?
What you give is what you get.
Look at your dress, how you look like.
You have a special dress somewhere, which you normally wear for festivals, special occasions,
weddings...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When it is time for thanksgiving, you bring change you received at the petrol station.
What you give is what you get.
You give change; you receive change.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Forgiveness.
You give change you received somewhere and you will receive change in return.
This is why what you have been receiving has not been satisfying you.
What you give to your friend is what you get from your friend.
What you give to your wife is what you get from your wife.
What you give to your husband is what you get from your husband.
What you give to your God is what you get from your God.
When we talk of giving, I am talking of forgiveness.
I’m talking of material and immaterial needs.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your time
When you give time that you don't need for an occasion.
When you study, the reward of that occasion...
Maybe you want to visit a friend and you check other commitments.
You go to visit your friend if there aren't any other commitments.
When you look at that relationship - the outcome of that relationship is according to
"what you give; you receive".
Thank you.
Take this word.
When you take this word, you will capture this all.
Like I have said, "Forgiveness and unforgiving spirit".
You will read the full detail in the book of Mark 11.
Hallelujah.
Regard God.
Regard God with your time.
Regard Him with your strength.